RODRIGO ABBÁS

E: rodrigoabbas@gmail.com Tucumán, Argentina

Professional Summary

Enthusiastic and highly skilled full stack software developer with +5 years on software industry, +4 years developing web applications, always providing excellent quality results and maintaining skills up-to-date. Strongly committed to team environment dynamics, with excellent problem-solving and debugging skills and a great willingness to learn.

Work Experience

SmartFlow - Software Engineer Dublin, Ireland 03/2019 - Present

- Developed and maintained internal tools for IoT devices data, using JavaScript, Python and Java.
- Provided full support to embedded systems.
- Performed tests on devices and software applications.
- Designed and coordinated several action plans.

Safigen - Full Stack Software Developer San Francisco, CA 02/2018 - 10/2018

- Designed and developed responsive front-end to show real-time IoT data with different useful features, with Vue JS.
- Developed several microservices to handle and process all incoming data and to support each feature, with Node JS.
- Designed and implemented SQL/NoSQL databases.
- Trained the new team members and staff.

Sovos - Software Engineer Tucumán, Argentina 12/2016 - 02/2018

- Improved a web application that handles, processes and graphically shows reports for data analysis. Developed several modules and a restful API. Worked with React JS and Node JS.
- Maintained and added lots of features to an existing web application. Developed with HTML and PHP. Simultaneousy, migrated its front-end to a React-Redux architecture.
- Provided training for new/other teams members.

Fcia Santo Domingo - Software Developer Tucumán, Argentina 06/2016 - 12/2016

 Designed and developed management application for branches, to keep track of sales, suppliers, inventory and additional information, with Node JS, HTML, Bootstrap and MySQL.

C: +5493816164583 / +353833944425 rodrigoabb.github.io/bio

Skills

Frontend

- JavaScript
- Vue 1S
- HTML
- React JS
- CSS
- Redux
- Bootstrap
- jQuery

Backend

- Node JS
- Java
- SQL / NoSQL
- C#
- API Design
- PHP

Frameworks / Utilities

- GIT
- CI/CD
- Mocha / Chai
- Jasmine / Jest

Others

- Software Design Web Development
- Database Design Agile Methodologies

Projects

mOsc - Tucumán, Argentina 08/2016 - 04/2017

- Designed and built an oscilloscope for Mobile Devices, using CIAA platform.
- Implemented Android UI, multiple functionalities and integration.
- · Created workflow system and communication protocol.

Post & Fun - Tucumán, Argentina 04/2015 - 10/2015

 Built a social network with HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PHP, MySQL and inhouse servers.

Education

Universidad Nacional De Tucumán

- Tucumán, Argentina

Bachelor of Engineering:

Computer Engineering

• Graduated on 06/2017

Languages

• Spanish: Native • English: Fluent